Guide to the John W. Gardner Papers SC0908
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2016-111
  - Books, 1998 May 05; 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Scientific / Military Advising, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Independent Sector, 1998 Aug 14; 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - WH Fellows MFB3 (1 of 1), 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - WH Fellows MFB3 (2 of 2), 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Presidents Reagan, Bush, Clinton, 1997 Feb 16; 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Ford, Carter, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Richard Nixon, Bobby Kennedy, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Johnson, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Presidents: LBJ, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Presidents: Hoover, Eisenhower, Kennedy, LBJ + Lady Bird, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - WWII Pearl Harbor/ Joc Taylor, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - HEW / Dept. Congress, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Family I, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Early Childhood, 1995 Jun; 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - WWII - Rev 2, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Scientific / Military Advising, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Books, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - IB-GMAS/Youth, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - WW2 Revisited, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Family, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Copy Carnegie, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Common Cause, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - UC, CC P. Copy, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Carnegie Years, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Family, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Carnegie, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - C. Cause, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Urban Coalition/ C. Cause, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - HEW - C., 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Transitions / Depression, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Stanford, 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Independent Sector, 1998 Aug 14; 1 audiocassette(s) (microcassette) (Box 48)
  - Stanford files, scrapbook, 1946-1965 (Box 49)
  - Scrapbook & Photographs (Box 50)
  - Photographs-HEW, 1977-1990 (Box 51)
  - Photographs & portraits, 1968-1979 (Box 53)
  - Photographs, portraits, and scrapbooks, 1979-1987 (Box 54)
  - Scrapbook, 1968-1975; 1990-1997 (Box 55)
  - Carnegie / "Extracurricular" (Box 57)
  - Carnegie / "Extracurricular" (Box 58)
  - Independent Sector (Box 59)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1969 (Box 61)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 61)
  - Common Cause / "Issues" (Box 62)
  - Common Cause / "Issues" / Independent sector (Including Watergate) (Box 63)
  - Independent Sector (Box 64)
  - Activities, after 1968 (Box 65)
  - Activities, after 1968 (Box 66)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1969 (Box 67)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1988 (Box 67)
  - John W. Gardner @ Stanford Collection, 1976-2000 (Box 69)
  - "An Experimental Study of the Luria Technique," Masters Thesis LSJU, 1936 (Box 69)
  - Reprints, Articles, Discussion papers, 1970s-2000s (Box 70, Box 72)
  - Common Cause scrapbook, 1975 Sep (Box 71)
  - JWG clippings, 1950s-1960s (Box 71)
  - Council on Foundations, 1987 (Box 71)
  - Excerpts: F-T, 1950s-1980s (Box 71)
  - Letters, cards, photographs, 1919-2002 (Box 73)
  - JWG memorial programs, 2002 (Box 73)
  - Kaufmann Foundation photographs, 2000 (Box 73)
  - JWG - Letters to mother, grandmother, 1944 (Box 73)
  - Citizen engagement, government, undated (Box 73)
  - LOTLC rejects, 1960s-1990s (Box 73)
  - Public service award from the Town Club of Scarsdale, 1968 (Box 73)
  - Letters, 1953-1982 (Box 74)
  - Women Bios (Box 74)
  - Leadership - Notes and Excerpts (Box 74)
  - Independent Sector - Task of Motivating, undated; 75_1; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 75)
  - Independent Sector - Release of Human Possibilities, undated; 75_2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 75)
  - ALF Forum, 1997; 75_3; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 75)
  - National Community Service Conference, 1992; 75_4; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 75)
  - The Assessment Center Method in Perspective, undated; 75_5; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 75)
  - JWG Interview produced for the Seminar on Philanthropy and Youth, 1997; 75_6; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 75)
  - Business Enterprise Award, 1995; 75_7; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 75)
  - Independent Sector - Release of Human Possibilities, undated; 75_8; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 75)
  - Columbia University Carnegie Corp. Project John Gardner, 1998-09-15; 76_1; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 76)
  - The Caring Institute 1991 National Caring Awards, 76_2; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 76)
  - UNC Charlotte 2003 Distinguished Service Award Peter J. Sidebottom, 76_3; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 76)
  - Independent Sector Annual Conference JW Gardner Award Luncheon, 1998; 76_4; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 76)
  - Gardner #1, undated; 76_5; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 76)
  - Independent Sector Annual Conference JW Gardner Award Luncheon, 1992; 76_6; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 76)
  - City Club of Portland Neal Keny-Guyer, 2001-10-05; 76_7; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 76)
  - Stanford Issues Ideas: Achieving Self-Renewal, undated; 76_8; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 76)
  - Independent Sector - Task of Motivating, 1990-2-22; 77_1; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 77)
  - Conversations with John W. Gardner, 2000; 77_2; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 77)
  - Independent Sector - Gardner Award Dinner, 1997; 77_3; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 77)
  - JWG Address on receiving University of Louisville Wilson W. Wyatt Award for Distinguished Public Service, 1989-11-16; 77_4; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 77)
  - Promoting Peace through Diversity, 1994; 77_5; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 77)
  - Celebrating the Life and Legacy John W. Gardner, 2002-4-16; 77_6; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 77)
  - Forum: David Gardner KQED, 1990-2-28; 78_1; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 78)
  - JG Interview by USIA, undated; 78_2; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 78)
  - "Leadership and the Common Good" JWG at the Commonwealth Club, 1990-1-12; 78_3; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 78)
  - "Ethics in Government: A Conversation with John W. Gardner", undated; 78_4; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 78)
  - "The Issue Behind the Issues" John Gardner, 1990-7-31; 78_5; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 78)
  - "The Pros and Conn", undated; 78_6; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 78)
  - "On Leadership," JWG, Recipient of the Carl Rogers Medal, 1990-7; 78_7; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 78)
  - SF Foundation with JG KQED, 1998-9-28; 78_8; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 78)
  - JG SCE Off-Site, undated; 78_9; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 78)
  - JG SCE Off-Site, undated; 79_10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 78)
  - Film Reels, undated (Box 80)
  - Biographical materials (Box 82)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2017-061
  - Photographs
    - Magazine covers, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Glamour shot at Aspen Institute, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Urban Coalition, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Gardner's boyhood WWII, 1910s-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Carnegie photographs, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - HEW photographs, 1965-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Independent Sector, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Common Cause photographs, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "A New Spirit is Stirring: Quotations from John W. Gardner, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Pictures with important people, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Gardner at Stanford, 1990-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)